<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><html xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://www.langmaster.com/new/author/coursemodelschema.xsd">
  <head>
    <title />
    <style />
  </head>
  <body xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <div id="SENTENCE_SEQUENCING">
    <h1 class="techInstr  ">{{th1|SENTENCE SEQUENCING}}</h1>
    <p>{{tp|Your task is to put the sentences into correct order. Proceed as follows:}}</p>
    <ol>
      <li>{{tli|Click on the sentence you wish to move. The sentence will be highlighted.}}</li>
      <li>{{tli1|Hold the left mouse button down and drag the sentence to the right place.}}</li>
      <li>{{tli2|When the mouse arrow points to the right place, release the left mouse button.}}</li>
      <li>{{tli3|The sentence will be moved.}}</li>
    </ol>
  </div>
  <div id="PICTURE_SEQUENCING">
    <h1 class="techInstr  ">{{th11|PICTURE SEQUENCING}}</h1>
    <p>{{tp1|Your task is to put the pictures into correct order. Proceed as follows:}}</p>
    <ol>
      <li>{{tli4|Click on the picture you wish to move. The picture will be highlighted.}}</li>
      <li>{{tli5|Hold the left mouse button down and drag the picture to the right place.}}</li>
      <li>{{tli6|When the mouse arrow points to the right place, release the left mouse button.}}</li>
      <li>{{tli7|The picture will be moved.}}</li>
    </ol>
  </div>
  <div id="WORD_SEQUENCING">
    <h1 class="techInstr  ">{{th12|WORD SEQUENCING}}</h1>
    <p>{{tp2|Your task is to put the words into correct order. Proceed as follows:}}</p>
    <ol>
      <li>{{tli8|Click on the word you wish to move. The word will be highlighted.}}</li>
      <li>{{tli9|Hold the left mouse button down and drag the word to the right place.}}</li>
      <li>{{tli10|When the mouse arrow points to the right place, release the left mouse button.}}</li>
      <li>{{tli11|The word will be moved.}}</li>
    </ol>
  </div>
  <div id="CHARACTER_SEQUENCING">
    <h1 class="techInstr  ">{{th13|CHARACTER SEQUENCING}}</h1>
    <p>{{tp3|Your task is to put the characters into correct order. Proceed as follows:}}</p>
    <ol>
      <li>{{tli12|Click on the character you wish to move. The character will be highlighted.}}</li>
      <li>{{tli13|Hold the left mouse button down and drag the character to the right place.}}</li>
      <li>{{tli14|When the mouse arrow points to the right place, release the left mouse button.}}</li>
      <li>{{tli15|The character will be moved.}}</li>
    </ol>
  </div>
  <div id="PAIRING">
    <h1 class="techInstr  ">{{th14|PAIRING}}</h1>
    <p>{{tp4|It is your task to connect (pair) left column items with items of the right column. Proceed as follows:}}</p>
    <ol>
      <li>{{tli16|Click on the item in the right column that you wish to move. The item will be highlighted.}}</li>
      <li>{{tli17|Hold the left mouse button down and drag the right column item next to the corresponding left column item.}}</li>
      <li>{{tli18|Release the left mouse button.}}</li>
      <li>{{tli19|The items will be linked.}}</li>
    </ol>
  </div>
  <div id="PAIRING_NEW">
    <h1 class="techInstr  ">{{th15|PAIRING}}</h1>
    <p>{{tp5|Your task is to pair the left column items with the items of the right column, so that the created pairs make sense. Proceed as follows:}}</p>
    <ol>
      <li>{{tli20|Left click an icon to select a left column item. The item will be highlighted.}}</li>
      <li>{{tli21|Click on the corresponding item in the right column.}}</li>
      <li>{{tli22|The item from the right column will be moved next to the correspoding item from the left column.}}</li>
      <li>{{tli23|The items will be linked.}}</li>
    </ol>
  </div>
  <div id="SINGLE_CHOICE">
    <h1 class="techInstr  ">{{th16|SINGLE CHOICE - ONE CORRECT ANSWER}}</h1>
    <p>{{tp6|Your task is to select the correct one out of several offered options. Proceed as follows:}}</p>
    <ol>
      <li>{{tli24|Left click the chosen item.}}</li>
      <li>{{tli25|If you wish to change your selection, click another option.}}</li>
    </ol>
  </div>
  <div id="SYLLABLE_SELECTION_ONE_CORRECT_OUT_OF_SEVERAL">
    <h1 class="techInstr  ">{{th17|TEXT SELECTION (MARKING) - ONE CORRECT ANSWER}}</h1>
    <p>{{tp7|Your task is to mark sentence parts, words, word parts or syllables while you may choose from several items but only one choice is correct. Proceed as follows:}}</p>
    <ol>
      <li>{{tli26|Place the mouse cursor over the item (sentence part, word, word part or syllable) you wish to select.}}</li>
      <li>{{tli27|Left click the item, it will be marked (selected).}}</li>
    </ol>
    <p>{{tp8|To change your selection select a different item.}}</p>
  </div>
  <div id="TEXT_SECTION_SELECTING_ONE_OR_MORE_CORRECT_ANSWERS">
    <h1 class="techInstr  ">{{th18|TEXT SELECTION (MARKING) - MULTIPLE CORRECT ANSWERS}}</h1>
    <p>{{tp9|Your task is to select sentence parts, words, word parts, syllables or characters. Proceed as follows:}}</p>
    <ol>
      <li>{{tli28|Place the mouse cursor over the item (sentence part, word, word part, syllable or character) you wish to select.}}</li>
      <li>{{tli29|Left click the item, it will be marked (selected).}}</li>
    </ol>
    <p>{{tp10|To cancel your selection click on selected item again.}}</p>
  </div>
  <div id="MULTIPLE_CHOICE_TWO_STATES">
    <h1 class="techInstr  ">{{th19|MULTIPLE CHOICE - MORE CORRECT ANSWERS}}</h1>
    <p>{{tp11|Your task is to select (mark) correct options. None of the options are selected by default. Proceed as follows:}}</p>
    <ol>
      <li>{{tli30|Left click the chosen item.}}</li>
      <li>{{tli31|The option will be selected (marked).}}</li>
    </ol>
    <p>{{tp12|To cancel your selection click on selected item again.}}</p>
  </div>
  <div id="SORTING_INTO_GROUPS_WRITING">
    <h1 class="techInstr  ">{{th110|SORTING INTO GROUPS (WRITING)}}</h1>
    <p>{{tp13|Your task is to write down the items into several groups. Proceed as follows:}}</p>
    <ol>
      <li>{{tli32|Click on the empty space in the group - a blinking cursor appears.}}</li>
      <li>{{tli33|Type in the item using your keyboard.}}</li>
    </ol>
    <p>{{tp14|To edit the item, select it and make correction.}}</p>
  </div>
  <div id="SORTING_INTO_GROUPS_DRAG_AND_DROP">
    <h1 class="techInstr  ">{{th111|SORTING INTO GROUPS (DRAG AND DROP)}}</h1>
    <p>{{tp15|Your task is to sort the items from the list into several groups. Proceed as follows:}}</p>
    <ol>
      <li>{{tli34|Click an item in the list. It will be highlighted.}}</li>
      <li>{{tli35|Hold your left mouse button down and drag the item to an empty space in the correct group.}}</li>
      <li>{{tli36|Release the left mouse button.}}</li>
      <li>{{tli37|The item will be moved into the chosen group and will be deactivated in the list.}}</li>
    </ol>
    <p>{{tp16|To recall the item from the group back to list, click on it.}}</p>
  </div>
  <div id="FILLING_IN">
    <h1 class="techInstr  ">{{th112|FILLING IN}}</h1>
    <p>{{tp17|Your task is to fill in the empty boxes within the text. Proceed as follows:}}</p>
    <ol>
      <li>{{tli38|Click on the empty space - a blinking cursor appears.}}</li>
      <li>{{tli39|Type in the text using your keyboard.}}</li>
    </ol>
  </div>
  <div id="FILLING_IN_FROM_A_LIST">
    <h1 class="techInstr  ">{{th113|FILLING IN FROM A LIST (DRAG &amp;amp; DROP)}}</h1>
    <p>{{tp18|Your task is to fill in the empty boxes within the text. You are given a list of items with different properties as described below:}}</p>
    <ol>
      <li>{{tli40|after dragging, the item in the list will be deactivated}}</li>
      <li>{{tli41|after dragging, the item in the list is not deactivated and can be used again}}</li>
    </ol>
    <p>{{tp19|Proceed as follows:}}</p>
    <ol>
      <li>{{tli42|Click an item in the list. It will be highlighted.}}</li>
      <li>{{tli43|Hold the left mouse button down and drag the item to the empty gap.}}</li>
      <li>{{tli44|Release the left mouse button. The item will be moved.}}</li>
    </ol>
    <p>{{tp20|To recall your selection, select and drag a different item from the list into its place.}}</p>
  </div>
  <div id="FILLING_IN_FROM_A_LIST_NEW">
    <h1 class="techInstr  ">{{th114|FILLING IN FROM A MENU}}</h1>
    <p>{{tp21|Your task is to fill in the empty boxes within the text. You are given a list of items with different properties as described below:}}</p>
    <ol>
      <li>{{tli45|after filling in to the text, the item in the menu is deactivated}}</li>
      <li>{{tli46|after filling in, the item in the list is not deactivated and can be used again}}</li>
    </ol>
    <p>{{tp22|Proceed as follows:}}</p>
    <ol>
      <li>{{tli47|Click on the empty gap - a menu with items appears}}</li>
      <li>{{tli48|Click a selected item. It will be filled in to the gap.}}</li>
    </ol>
    <p>{{tp23|To change the filled in item, fill in another one into its place.}}</p>
  </div>
  <div id="TRUE_FALSE_SENTENCES">
    <h1 class="techInstr  ">{{th115|TRUE/FALSE SENTENCES}}</h1>
    <p>{{tp24|Your task is to decide whether the sentences are true or false. Every sentence is marked with an icon. Proceed as follows:}}</p>
    <ol>
      <li>{{tli49|If the sentence is false, skip it.}}</li>
      <li>{{tli50|If the sentence is true, click on it. It will be selected (marked).}}</li>
      <li>{{tli51|To cancel your selection click on selected item again.}}</li>
    </ol>
  </div>
  <div id="TRUE_FALSE_SENTENCES_NEW">
    <h1 class="techInstr  ">{{th116|TRUE/FALSE SENTENCES}}</h1>
    <p>{{tp25|Your task is to decide whether the sentences are true or false. Proceed as follows:}}</p>
    <ol>
      <li>{{tli52|If the sentence is true, click on True.}}</li>
      <li>{{tli53|If the sentence is false, click on False.}}</li>
    </ol>
  </div>
  <div id="YES_NO_QUESTIONS">
    <h1 class="techInstr  ">{{th117|YES/NO QUESTIONS}}</h1>
    <p>{{tp26|Your task is to decide whether the answers to the questions are Yes or No.}}</p>
    <ol>
      <li>{{tli54|If the correct answer is Yes, click on YES.}}</li>
      <li>{{tli55|If the correct answer is No, click on NO.}}</li>
    </ol>
  </div>
  <div id="DICTATION">
    <h1 class="techInstr  ">{{th118|DICTATION}}</h1>
    <p>{{tp27|Your task is to fill in the empty boxes with the words or sentences you hear. Proceed as follows:}}</p>
    <ol>
      <li>{{tli56|Listen to the word or the sentence.}}</li>
      <li>{{tli57|Click on the empty space - a blinking cursor appears.}}</li>
      <li>{{tli58|Type in the text that you hear using your keyboard.}}</li>
    </ol>
    <p>{{tp28|To edit the item, select it and make correction.}}</p>
  </div>
  <div id="CORRECTION">
    <h1 class="techInstr  ">{{th119|MODIFICATION (CORRECTION) OF THE TEXT}}</h1>
    <p>{{tp29|Your task is to rewrite the words in the gap into the correct form. Proceed as follows:}}</p>
    <ol>
      <li>{{tli59|Click on the text you wish to change - a blinking cursor appears.}}</li>
      <li>{{tli60|Rewrite the text into the correct form. It is possible, that no changes will be needed.}}</li>
    </ol>
  </div>
  <div id="INFORMATION">
    <h1 class="techInstr  ">{{th120|INFORMATION}}</h1>{{tpage_instruction|Your task is to carefully read the information on this page.}}<br /></div>
  <div id="SHOW_THE_HIDDEN_TEXT">
    <h1 class="techInstr  ">{{th121|DISPLAYING THE HIDDEN TEXT}}</h1>
    <p>{{tp30|Exercise with hidden text. To unhide it, click on the "eye" icon.}}</p>
  </div>
  <div id="SOUND_PLAYBACK">
    <h1 class="techInstr  ">{{th122|SOUND PLAYBACK}}</h1>
    <p>{{tp31|Exercises with a sound-track can be recognized by their “sound mark”. There are two types of sound mark:}}</p>
    <ol>
      <li>{{tli61|A big sound mark is used to replay longer recordings (articles, dialogues). In this case you cannot see the text, you can only hear it.}}</li>
      <li>{{tli62|A small sound mark is used to replay words or sentences. You can see the text and listen to it at the same time.}}</li>
      <li>{{tli63|To play the sound, click the sound mark. To stop replaying, click elsewhere on the screen.}}</li>
    </ol>
  </div>
  <div id="VIDEO_PLAYBACK">
    <h1 class="techInstr  ">{{th123|VIDEO PLAYBACK}}</h1>
    <p>{{tp32|To play the video you can use the following controls from the bottom control bar.}}</p>
    <ol>
      <li>{{tli64|To start playing the video, click Play (&amp;gt;).}}</li>
      <li>{{tli65|To stop playing, click Pause (||).}}</li>
      <li>{{tli66|Use the arrows: |&amp;lt;&amp;lt;, &amp;gt;&amp;gt;|, to move one replica back or forward.}}</li>
      <li>{{tli67|Use the arrows: &amp;lt;&amp;lt;, &amp;gt;&amp;gt;, to move one sentence (part of the replica) back or forward.}}</li>
      <li>{{tli68|Use T (icon) to display or hide the subtitles.}}</li>
      <li>{{tli69|Use the microphone icon, to run the Listen&amp;amp;Talk application for the current sentence.}}</li>
      <li>{{tli70|Use the speaker icon to turn the sound on/off.}}</li>
    </ol>
  </div>
  <div id="VOCABULARY">
    <h1 class="techInstr  ">{{th124|VOCABULARY}}</h1>
    <p>{{tp33|When learning new vocabulary, proceed as follows:}}</p>
    <ol>
      <li>{{tli71|Read the new word (phrase) and the corresponding translation.}}</li>
      <li>{{tli72|Click the speaker icon and listen to the correct pronunciation.}}</li>
      <li>{{tli73|Click the microphone icon and practice correct pronunciation using Listen&amp;amp;Talk application.}}</li>
    </ol>
  </div>
  <div id="LISTEN_TALK">
    <h1 class="techInstr  ">{{th125|LISTEN &amp;amp; TALK}}</h1>
    <p>{{tp34|When practicing your pronunciation, proceed as follows:}}</p>
    <ol>
      <li>{{tli74|Click the Play icon and listen to the original recording.}}</li>
      <li>{{tli75|Click the Record icon and record your own pronunciation. To stop recording, click the icon again.}}</li>
      <li>{{tli76|Click the next Play icon, replay your recording and compare it with the original one.}}</li>
      <li>{{tli77|Repeat the whole process until you are satisfied with the result.}}</li>
    </ol>
  </div>
  <div id="FLASH_PLAYBACK">
    <h1 class="techInstr  ">{{th126|FLASH PLAYBACK}}</h1>
    <p>{{tp35|TODO}}</p>
  </div>
</body>
</html>